Mohammad Yasir Azeem



yasirazeem44@gmail.com



+966571739502



linkedin.com/in/mohammad-yasirazeem-047498219



https://www.techieyasir.com/

Summary

Obsessed Cloud Enthusiast with an impressive AWS home lab. Dedicated IT professional with 7+ years of experience providing unforgettable experiences to clients while maintaining an addiction to learning Cloud technologies and DevOps. Plagued with the overwhelming urge to tinker, figure things out, and build enterpriselevel AWS infrastructures.

Cloud Experience

AWS LABS

- Built a hacking lab in AWS to simulate an enterprise network and vulnerable machines using Kali Linux.
- Built a web server using Amazon Linux, Ubuntu, and Centos on EC2 Instance.
- Built an Application Server on EC2 Instance Using Tomcat.
- Deployed a domain controller on Windows Server 2022 along with two Windows Server 2019 machines utilizing AWS Virtual Machine. Deployed two Windows 11 VMs and joined the domain.
- Created multiple VPCs within the Regions to simulate multiple network subnets.
- Utilized CloudWatch to monitor performance and create alerts.

HOME LAB - VIRTUALIZATION ON HOME SERVER

- Installed and configured Proxmox on a home server, setting up hosts, networking, and storage.
- Deployed Virtual machines, Ubuntu servers in my home lab for DevOps Learning.
- Home lab for GIT-Hub, GITLAB and JENKINS CICD.
- · Home lab For Ansible. Docker.

AWS Solution Architect Associate (Udemy)

- Microsoft Server 2012- system administration (Udemy)
- Linux server
- APACHE- TOMCAT, APACHE-WEBSERVER (HTTPD)
- · Git, GitHub Gitlab
- · Docker, Docker-hub
- · Ansible, chef
- Kubernetes
- Jenkins CICD, GIT-HUB CICD
- VMWARE HYPERVISOR
- Proxmox
- Python
- HTML
- MySQL

Experience

Information Technology System Engineer

AL-Yamama Company

Nov 2021 - Present (1 year 7 months)

PROJECT -King Abdul Aziz Center for World Culture (SAUDI ARAMCO PROJECT)

Routinely engage with the Networking Team to learn additional skills and help with the daily administration of Cisco switches and routers.

- Working as Maintenance Engineer for Honeywell BMS Server Security Server and Lighting Servers.
- Implement new server-based technologies as part of the IT department's strategic plans.
- Create and implement Active Directory Group Policies as per organizational requirements.
- · Manage onboarding/offboarding processes, be the main contact with the HR Team and hold responsible for all IT equipment,
- · Created a wiki of common desktop/application fixes for the support team, cutting ticket time to close in half.
- Resolve 20+ trouble tickets per day through efficient triaging of problems.
- Managing day-to-day service desk team, coaching them, developing their skills, and building internal collaboration.

Information Technology Administrator

Glocal University

Feb 2015 - Jul 2021 (6 years 6 months)

- MS SQL Database Management.
- Create and manage Organizational Units, Manage Users.
- · Group policy management.
- Deploy software with Group policy.
- Backup and Recovery Management
- Installation and Configuration of Active Directory / DNS / DHCP / AV Servers
- LAN installation, Routing, use of wireshark software.
- · Cisco Routers DHCP configuration by using CLI.
- Experience in Server Hardware Knowledge, Monitoring & Administration
- Troubleshoot server network configuration problems
- Database Management. MS SQL server.
- configuration & troubleshooting of Cisco Switches, routers, firewall.
- Networks protocol support and IP address configuration. Assist user in daily operational issues
- · Performed hardware and software support and installation, Replaced defective or inadequate software packages
- Handling Wi-Fi (wireless internet) and rectify the problem.
- Handling Department Asset Management.
- Handling Department Budget Management & coordinating billing process.

Education



🔃 Uttrakhand Technical University, Dehradun

Master's degree, Wireless communication Jul 2012 - Jun 2014



🔃 Uttrakhand Technical University, Dehradun

B.Tech, Electrical, Electronics and Communications Engineering Jul 2007 - Jun 2011

Licenses & Certifications

- Ultimate AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate SAA-C03 Udemy UC-ee6dff1e-9ed6-4a47-ac9b-ccd097a92450
- Windows Server 2012 System Administration Udemy UC-a7149bcd-3c38-45d8-892c-24862b3d42b3
- **Azure Cloud** Udemy UC-8325553f-cb01-4ccc-b828-bee08331b6c0
- Amazon Elastic Container Service (AWS ECS) KodeKloud 2D0D3B59A3D2-2DF61BAD93E0-2D0B1CB57984

Skills

Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Linux Server • Windows System Administration • GitHub • Docker Products • Ansible • Tomcat • Jenkins • Microsoft Azure • Python (Programming Language)